<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Mconomy</string>
    <!-- Strings related to login -->
    <string name="autentificare">Authenticate</string>
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="mconomy">Mconomy</string>
    <string name="microeconomie">Microeconomy</string>
    <string name="inapoi">Back</string>
    <string name="rentabilitate">Rentability</string>
    <string name="informatii">Informations</string>
    <string name="calculeaza">Calculus</string>
    <string name="adauga_produs">Add product</string>
    <string name="_0_00">0.00</string>
    <string name="inregistrare">Record</string>
    <string name="confirati_parola">Confirm password</string>
    <string name="actiuni">Stocks</string>
    <string name="economii_nationale">National economies</string>
    <string name="deconectare">Log out</string>
    <string name="salveaza_lista_si_incepe_o_sesiune_noua">Save the current list and start a new one</string>
    <string name="vezi_listele">View the lists</string>
    <string name="mconomy_app">Mconomy App</string>
    <string name="cheltuieli_guvernamentale">Governmental expenditure</string>
    <string name="importuri">Imports</string>
    <string name="consum">Consumption</string>
    <string name="exporturi">Exports</string>
    <string name="completati_campurile_goale_pentru_a_primi_informatii">Complete all the fields</string>
    <string name="investitii">Invests</string>
    <string name="tipul_economiei_va_aparea_aici_dupa_generarea_calcului">** Here will appear the economy type</string>
    <string name="_0_mil">0 mil</string>
    <string name="banca">Bank</string>
    <string name="credite">Credits</string>
    <string name="imprumuturi">Loans</string>
    <string name="profit_investitii">Profit/Invests</string>
    <string name="afla_ce_iti_poate_oferi_banca">See what the bank`s role</string>
    <string name="pib">GDP :</string>
    <string name="pgb">GGP :</string>
    <string name="pnb">GNP :</string>
    <string name="content_info"><it>Microeconoy</it> deals with the study of the economic behavior of different consumers (budgetary theory), of the firm (production theory) and the problem of dividing limited goods and limited income. In microeconomics, individuals are seen as labor, as consumers of produced goods, which they consume in order to maximize their utility. Production units use the factors of production such as labor, capital, scientific progress with the aim of maximizing profit.</string>
    <string name="li_inventar"><b><li>Store inventory:</li></b> is a current stock management process. Products will be added to a list after fe performs the product calculation operation between price and quantity. The list will be added to a global database</string>
    <string name="utilitatile_microeconomiei">Microeconomics utilities and information about the functionalities in the application</string>
    <string name="li_rentabilitate"><b><li>Profitability:</li></b> it measures the rate of return on assets of institutions or companies. It is determined as the ratio between net profit and assets at the end of the period or net profit and average assets (ROA).</string>
    <string name="li_cost_de_oportunitate"><b><li>Opportunity cost:</li></b> represents the value of the best of the sacrificed chances, which is given up when some choice is made. In other words, he measures the greatest loss among the options sacrificed, considering the choice made to be the "win." It is the value of the sacrifices of the actual choices, given the given resources. The opportunity cost of a good is given by what is sacrificed to obtain this good. Choices or decisions have a certain cost because when a particular decision is made and one option is chosen, the others are sacrificed.</string>

    <string name="utilitatile_macroeconomiei">Macroeconomics utilities and information about the functionalities in the application.</string>
    <string name="content_info2"><it>Macroeconomy</it> is a field of economic sciences. Unlike microeconomics, macroeconomics works with aggregate quantities, researching the behavior of the economy in general, such as total income or employment, the inflation rate or business cycles. Macroeconomics tries to find explanations for these oscillations, to find the relevant controlling factors and to establish their dependencies.</string>
    <string name="li_banca"><b><li>Bank:</li></b> is a financial institution whose main activity is attracting deposits and granting loans. Banks are organized in the form of a joint-stock company and operate under the supervision of the central bank. Banking, including deposit-taking and lending as core banking operations, as well as related and ancillary banking services, is a highly regulated public interest economic activity. Banks are established in most legislations in the form of joint-stock companies, and upon incorporation the founders must have a share capital that far exceeds the requirements of an ordinary joint-stock company.</string>
    <string name="li_economii_nationale"><b><li>The national economy:</li></b>  represents a generalized, complex system of economic-social activities arising and carried out between economic agents in a state framework, determined from a historical, political, social and economic point of view, based on economic resources (quantitative component) and behavioral motivations (component qualitative) of economic agents. The structure of the economy reflects the totality of its component elements and the relationships between them viewed in their interdependence and integrity.</string>
    <string name="li_asigurari"><b><li>Isurance:</li></b>it is a means of protection against financial loss. It is a form of risk management, used primarily to insure against the risk of contingent or uncertain loss. An entity that provides insurance is known as an insurer, insurance company, insurance carrier, or underwriter. A person or entity that buys insurance is known as an insured or an insurance policyholder. The insurance transaction involves insurance assuming a relatively small, guaranteed and known loss in the form of payment to the insurer in exchange for the insurer`s promise to compensate the insured in the event of a covered loss. The loss may or may not be financial, but must be reduced to financial terms and usually involves something in which the insured has an established insurable interest by property, possession or pre-existing relationship.</string>
    <string name="cantitate">Quantity :</string>
    <string name="rezultat">Result :</string>
    <string name="nume_produs">Product name</string>
    <string name="pret">Price :</string>
    <string name="rezultat_acumulat">Cumulative Result :</string>
    <string name="descriere">description</string>
    <string name="produs">Product:</string>
    <string name="warning_text">** The fields that will not have values will be left empty (there is no need to add the value 0)</string>
    <string name="imagina_i_v_o_companie_american_care_construie_te_o_fabric_de_tricouri_n_vietnam_n_acest_caz_ceea_ce_produce_aceast_fabric_va_fi_num_rat_n_pnb_sua_dar_nu_i_n_pnb_vietnam_deoarece_de_i_acesta_din_urm_este_locul_de_produc_ie_compania_este_sua_pe_de_alt_parte_produc_ia_acestei_fabrici_va_fi_luat_n_calcul_n_pib_ul_vietnamului_dar_nu_n_pib_ul_statelor_unite">Imagine an American company building a T-shirt factory in Vietnam. In this case, what this factory produces will be counted in the US GNP, but not in Vietnam`s GNP, because although the latter is the place of production, the company is the US. On the other hand, the output of this factory will be counted in the GDP of Vietnam, but not in the GDP of the United States.</string>
    <string name="produsul_national_brut_pnb"><li>Gross national product (GNP):</li></string>
    <string name="este_suma_preturilor_finale_ale_tuturor_bunurilor_si_serviciilor_produse_de_o_tara_intr_o_anumita_perioada_de_obicei_un_an_utilizand_resurse_proprii">It is the sum of the final prices of all goods and services produced by a country in a certain period (usually a year) using its own resources.</string>
    <string name="produsul_intern_brut_pib"><li>Gross domestic product (GDP):</li></string>
    <string name="vezi_ce_semnifica_acesti_indicatori">See what these indicators mean</string>
    <string name="venituri_rezidenti_din_strainatate">Resident incomes from abroad</string>
    <string name="venituri_rezidenti_straini">Foreign resident incomes</string>
    <string name="inventar_nou">New inventory</string>
    <string name="sterge">Delete</string>
    <string name="_0">0</string>
    <string name="scrie_aici_numarul_sesiunii_facturii">Write the session/invoice number here</string>
    <string name="selecteaza_rata_dobanzii">Select the interest rate (%) :</string>
    <string name="suma_imprumutata">Loan amount</string>
    <string name="selecteaza_tipul_perioadei_imprumutului">Select the time period type</string>
    <string name="lunar">monthly</string>
    <string name="rata">Interest rate</string>
    <string name="nr_luna_an_sem_trim">month/year/sem/trim</string>
    <string name="suma">Amount</string>
    <string name="amortizarea_actiunii">Liquidation</string>
    <string name="introdu_nr_de_variante">Enter no of variants :</string>
    <string name="introdu_nr_de_sortimente">Enter no of assortments :</string>
    <string name="intro_rentabilitate">Margin rates are determined as the ratio of various margins to turnover (the operating income that generated these margins). They are also called commercial rates of return.</string>
    <string name="capitaluri_proprii">Equity capital</string>
    <string name="profit_net">Net income</string>
    <string name="active_totale">Total assets</string>
    <string name="dobanda">Interest rate</string>
    <string name="datorii">Liability</string>
    <string name="aici_vor_aparea_rezultatele_in_urma_calculelor_executate">The results will appear here</string>
    <string name="fluxul_pretului_pe_3_zile">Price flow records in the past 3 days</string>
    <string name="chart_actiuni">Stocks chart</string>
    <string name="rata_dobanzii">Interest rate</string>
    <string name="rentabilitatea_actiunilor">Stocks rentability</string>
    <string name="rentabilitatea_financiara">Financial rentability</string>
    <string name="sterge_inregistrarea">Delete the record</string>
    <string name="suma_totala">Total amount:</string>
    <string name="numar_produse">Number of products:</string>
    <string name="sesiune_de_inventar">Inventory session:</string>
    <string name="textview">TextView</string>
    <string name="mesaj">Message</string>
    <string name="conectat">Connected</string>
    <string name="setari">Settings</string>
    <string name="schimba_parola"><li>Change password</li></string>
    <string name="trimite_cerere_pentru_schimbarea_parolei">Send a request to change your current password</string>
    <string name="apasa_pe_acest_buton_pentru_a_trimite_o_cerere_de_schimbare_a_parolei_curente.">Press this button to send a request to change the current password</string>
    <string name="acasa">Home</string>
    <string name="suport"><li>Support</li></string>
    <string name="pentru_suport_tehnic_scrie_un_mesaj_in_casuta_de_mai_jos_vei_primi_feedback_ul_pe_adresa_curenta_de_mail">For technical support, write a message in the box below. You will receive the feedback on the current email address.</string>
    <string name="scrie_aici_mesajul">Write here your message</string>
    <string name="trimite">Send</string>
    <string name="perioada_imprumut_credit">Credit loan period</string>
    <string name="rata_dobanzii_credit">Credit interest rate</string>
    <string name="vizualizeaza_statistici_in_timp_real">View real-time charts</string>
    <string name="tesla_inc">Tesla, Inc.</string>
    <string name="selecteaza_limba"><li>Select the language</li></string>
    <string name="alege_aplicatia">Choose the application</string>
    <string name="nu_exista_app_comp">There is no application to open the message! Download one from the Play Store (ex: Gmail, Yahoo Mail)</string>
    <string name="err_no_text_send_mail">To send an email to the support center, you need to enter a message here!</string>
    <string name="text_gol">The text is empty!</string>
    <string name="info">info</string>
    <string name="inventar">Inventory</string>
    <string name="cost_de_oportunitate">Opportunity cost</string>
    <string name="parola">Password</string>
    <string name="vizualizeaza_stiatistica">View the statistics</string>
    <string name="macroeconomie">Macroeconomy</string>
    <string name="prompt_email">Email</string>
    <string name="prompt_password">Password</string>
    <string name="action_sign_in">Sign in or register</string>
    <string name="action_sign_in_short">Sign in</string>
    <string name="welcome">"Welcome!"</string>
    <string name="invalid_username">Not a valid username</string>
    <string name="invalid_password">Password must be >5 characters</string>
    <string name="login_failed">"Login failed"</string>
    <string name="ramai_conectat_ask">Stay connected ?</string>
    <string name="nu">No</string>
    <string name="da">Yes</string>
    <string name="ajutor">Help</string>
    <string name="credit_imobiliar">can be used to purchase a property (house or apartment) or another real estate loan held at another bank.</string>
    <string name="credit_ipotecar">For credit approval, your net monthly salary must be at least 1,524 lei. If you obtain income from several employers, their accumulation is accepted as long as at least one of the incomes is equivalent to the minimum wage in the economy.</string>
    <string name="credit_pe_viata">The only cost of insurance is the monthly premium. That is 0.138% of the value of the loan balance. And it will decrease with the repayment of the loan. An indicative calculation: for a loan of 20,000 lei, the payment amount for the first month is 27.60 lei. Afterwards, it will decrease in proportion to the remaining amount to be repaid.</string>
    <string name="credit_obligatar">Bonded credit represents a group of credit operations with a secular existence that refers to credit relationships in which the partners are state institutions or economic enterprises as debtors, which issue the bonds, in this capacity, on the one hand, and creditors, underwriters and holders of these bonds, who thus engage their capital, in order to obtain a secure income in the main form of interest.</string>
    <string name="credit_bancar">Credit through which the bank makes available to the applicant sums of money that will be returned at a fixed term (loan of money). The bank credit is based on a contract between the bank and a client, who can be a natural person, a legal person or an institution Of the state.</string>
    <string name="credit_comercial">Trade credit is an essential tool for companies that want to conquer new markets and build a long-term business relationship. Indispensable in certain sectors, such as the distribution sector or the construction sector, trade credit involves various risks, but there are ways to effectively control them.</string>
    <string name="credit_de_consum">Consumer loans are those loans made for the purchase of consumer goods or services. They are frequently used to buy cars, travel or household items.</string>
    <string name="credit_nebancar">A non-bank loan is characterized by the following: you will receive the money quickly; you need a small number of documents to receive the non-bank loan; all the steps to obtain the non-bank loan are completed online, directly in front of the computer. A bank loan, unlike a non-bank loan, obliges you to: present a large number of documents that are the subject of eligibility in order to receive the loan; bank loans are much more difficult to obtain than non-bank loans; practicing commissions based on which bank employees check the file of the future beneficiary; the steps you follow for the granting of bank loans are carried out at the headquarters of the respective bank.</string>
    <string name="ipotecar">Mortgage</string>
    <string name="imobiliar">Immobile</string>
    <string name="pe_viata">For life</string>
    <string name="obligatar">Bond</string>
    <string name="de_consum">For consumption</string>
    <string name="bancar">Banking</string>
    <string name="comercial">Commercial</string>
    <string name="nebancar">No banking</string>
    <string name="max_10_ani">maximum 10 years</string>
    <string name="max_15_ani">maximum 15 years</string>
    <string name="max_20_ani">maximum 20 years</string>
    <string name="max_25_ani">maximum 25 years</string>
    <string name="max_30_ani">maximum 30 years</string>
    <string name="max_35_ani">maximum 35 years</string>
    <string name="pe_toata_viata">throughout life</string>
    <string name="perioada_imprumut">Loan period:</string>
    <string name="sterge_tot_mesajul">Delete entire message</string>
</resources>